Hello friends. First video in a while,
and that is because I've been working on
version 1.1 of my skills repo. It has an
astonishing amount of stuff in there.
There is an entire new approach to
grilling, which probably deserves its
own video, but I'll try and squeeze it
in here. There is a bunch of new changes
to existing skills, including a rename
of two main flow skills. There is just
really way too much for me to summarize
in this intro, so you're just going to
have to watch the video to find out. We
can see the PR is literally ready to
merge now. So, why not? Let's actually
freaking merge this thing. And just like
that, we have our version 1.1 ready to
go. Let's start with the two that are
probably going to be most annoying for
you, and the most like, why did he do
this? And there is a very specific
reason that I did it, which is that two
skills have been renamed. For instance,
two PRD has now been renamed to two
spec. And if we go up one level, then we
go to two issues has been renamed to two
tickets. The reason I've done this is
that this has just been bugging me for a
long time. The thing that we were
creating in two PRD wasn't actually a
PRD. It was a spec. A product
requirements document kind of describes
more things about the actual product
itself, whereas we were allowing things
to leak into the PRD that weren't
necessarily PRDs. So, for a long time
I've wanted to rename it to two spec,
cuz that's what we were creating. We
were just creating a specification.
Specification is a much broader term
that actually entails what we were
building.
for a thing we want to build. That can
be technical, it can be non-technical,
and it can blend the two. It doesn't
really matter. When it came to two
issues, two issues always felt like it
was biased towards GitHub and linear
that use issues, but really we want this
to be tickets. You have a spec, and then
underneath the spec you have the tickets
that are the journey that you
take to actually enact the spec and
create it. This has been annoying me for
a long time, and finally it no longer
annoys me. It brings me joy. Now, one
irritating thing about this rename is
that you will need to probably delete
those skills and re-add them. This means
you'll need to run NPX skills add Map Po
skills. I'm pretty sure that this
skills installer won't pick up the
rename, so it won't try to update to PRD
to turn it into to spec. You get what I
mean. And so, running this command is
the safest way to grab all of these new
skills cuz you get to just pick and
choose which ones you want. And once
you've done that, you should probably go
through a pass through your skills
folder and just check that no bad ones
are still in there. So, you want to make
sure that you're intentionally grabbing
all the right skills. The next change is
that I've fixed a couple of bugs that
people were having with grill me and
grill with docs. Both of them rely on
this kind of central reference grilling
skill that kind of show shows the LLM
how to grill a person. I've sharpened up
this line here saying asking multiple
questions at once is bewildering. Even
with this direction to ask questions one
at a time, it was still occasionally
just going
to have multiple questions at once. So,
I've told it why we don't want multiple
questions at once. We've also added a
confirmation gate on the end. Do not
enact the plan until I confirm we've
reached a shared understanding. Lots of
people on different models were
reporting that the grilling session
would just end and then it would just go
straight into implementation. So, this
is just an extra little gate there.
Finally, on some situations, it would
just grill itself, which is very, very
odd. Not something I've noticed or seen
in my personal thing, but I I can only
get a small subset of how these skills
are actually used. So, I've basically
tried to use a couple of leading words
to indicate the difference between facts
and decisions. So, sometimes it was
using the previous phrasing here by just
exploring the code base and grilling
itself. This was especially happening
with Fable, actually. And so, I've
decided to make a distinction between
facts, so facts that are things you find
yourself by exploring the code base, and
decisions. So, decisions are needed to
be made by the user. So, just a couple
of sentences, added a couple of things
changed around, and this has made it a
lot more consistent. Definitely getting
a lot fewer complaints about those weird
issues happening. The next thing to say
is that I've added a couple of skills
that really just take the process that
was primarily a planning process, didn't
really hold your hand into
implementation, and turn it into a
proper software development life cycle.
So, many folks ask me, "What is the
flow? What is the main flow you're
supposed to use with the skills?" And
first of all, I mean, this is it. We
have number one, you're supposed to
instead of using plan mode, you get an
agent to grill you. And it uses these
couple of docs to add a glossary, to
kind of understand you better as you go
along, and also add architectural
decision records so you can capture the
non-obvious stuff. The stuff that goes
in the growth for docs then goes into a
spec, as we saw before. That spec kind
of defines the destination, where you're
going. Then, you turn that spec into
individual tickets so you can spread the
development of it out over multiple
agent sessions. That's the purpose of to
tickets. You then implement each one of
those tickets with a implement skill.
And the implement skill is very, very
simple. It just looks like this.
Implement the work described by the user
in the spec or tickets. Use TDD where
possible at pre-agreed seams. That's a
nice one. And run type checking
regularly, single test files regularly,
and full test suite once at the end.
Once done, use code review to review the
work, and then commit your work to the
current branch. I almost didn't make a
skill for this because it's really
simple, right? It's just mostly relying
on the agent's priors, on its, you know,
on the harness, kind of teaching it what
to do. And I didn't honestly think we
needed a skill here, but folks kept
asking me, "What's the flow? What's the
flow here?" And so, I figured just an
implement skill, make it nice and
simple, right? At each stage of the
process, call this skill. So, that means
implement earns its place here because
you know, okay, once we got two tickets,
then we just got to implement each
ticket in a separate coding session.
Implement then itself calls code review.
And code review, I graduated this out of
in progress on version one. So, it's
been around for a little bit, but I have
made some updates to it in this version
two. The theory of the code review skill
is that it reviews code on two axes. So,
it does a sub agent for each one of
these. The first one is the standards
axis. Does the code conform to this
repo's documented coding standards? So,
if you've got a coding standards.md file
somewhere in your repo, then it will
read that and check against those. I
generally think that coding standards
belong outside of your agents.md file.
They're supposed to be somewhere
separate, and the code review point is
where they're most useful. And then,
once you've done the standards, you then
go on to the spec. Does the code
faithfully implement the originating
issue or PR or spec? They both run as
parallel sub agents, and it does a
process here where it walks through each
part. Now, the thing that's cool and new
about this skill is that I've been
reading Martin Fowler's refactoring
again. And what I decided to do is
Martin Fowler names a bunch of different
smells that the agent can identify in
bad code. Refactoring is such an old
book, such a well-cited book, that these
uh kind of smells are deep in the
agent's priors. And so, all you need to
do is kind of invoke the idea Okay,
mysterious name or duplicated code or
feature envy, data clumps, primitive
obsession, repeated switches, divergent
change, speculative generality, message
chains. You see what I mean? Like, these
are all deep in the agent's kind of
knowledge base, and all we got to do is
just really describe them in a sentence.
And what I found is that leads the word
or leads the agent to repeat that word
back to you and say, "Yes, I found some
message chains. I need to remove them. I
found a middle man situation. I need to
uh fix that." So, I tested this for a
couple of weeks and it was outrageously
useful. It was really, really nice at
improving the quality of my code and
it's really cheap to add here, just kind
of like 10 lines. But, let's go and talk
about the one that I'm really, really
excited about, which is a whole new
change to the way that we kick off and
shape specs. So, the pre-spec bit. In
other words, it goes here where it may,
in some situations, replace Grill with
Docs. And it's called Wayfinder. I will
make an entire post uh entire video
about Wayfinder, but uh suffice to say
is that I would love for you, in
situations where you're thinking about
using Grill with Docs, instead to
default to Wayfinder instead. What
Wayfinder does is it's designed for
situations where you have a ton of stuff
that you want to plan, but and too big
for one agent session. In other words,
you're going to blow out of the smart
zone of the agent or you might even blow
out of the context window of the agent.
You need to split it into multiple parts
in order to figure out where you're
going. A loose idea has arrived, too big
for one agent session and wrapped in
fog. The way from here to the
destination isn't visible yet. This
skill charts the way as a shared map on
the repo's issue tracker, then works its
tickets one at a time until the route is
clear. These maps are saved in GitHub
issues. For instance, this is one on the
Sandcastle repo where we're doing a
spike to think about maybe pulling in
the AI SDK as a dependency, a big, big
change. And so, you can see there are no
decisions that have um been made so far
and all of the decisions that need to be
made are saved in sub-issues. And these
sub-issues have blocking relationships.
So, we can see that no decision can be
made here before we make this key
decision at the start. Each one of these
decisions is scoped to be the size of an
agent session. And we can see that
they're labeled as different types here.
So, for instance, this one is labeled as
a research task. So, this is really an
AFK task for the agent to go off, do
some research, and then come back. This
one I think is a research as well. This
one is a research task, and this one is
a grilling task. So, this one needs a
grilling session to be done here. I
think these are all grillers. We can see
these defined in the ticket types down
here. So, we have research, we have
grilling, we also have prototype as
well. So, this is something I've been
really advocating for recently is doing
more prototyping before you get to a
spec. The idea is you raise the fidelity
of the discussion by making a cheap,
rough, concrete artifact to react to. An
outline, rough tech stub, UI logic code
via the prototype skill. We'll get to
that in a minute. Links to the prototype
as an asset. And it says use when how
should it look or how should it behave
is a key question. And this is essential
for almost anything that touches
front-end code. So, I would definitely
be recommending using Wayfinder for
anything that touches the front-end. The
final one here is just tasks. So, config
that needs to be set up, um provisioning
access, you know, moving data into the
shape, you know, all the sort of boring
stuff that doesn't need a grilling
decision and can't really be automated
by AI. What you end up with is after all
of these tickets are closed, all of that
information gets saved onto the map with
the original tickets as kind of primary
sources for what was captured. And you
can then take this map and just turn it
into a spec in the regular way. What I
found that instead of having the kind of
anxiety of managing my session with
grill with docs having to hand off,
worry about the smart zone. With
Wayfinder, it's kind of all managed for
me. I just get to close a session, open
up the next Wayfinder ticket. It's all
saved in GitHub, so it's collaborative.
You can share it across your team. And
once the map is done, once it's
complete, you just go to to spec, and
you're good to go. To support the
Wayfinder skill, we have a new research
skill, which is very small, very handy
for when you just need to do a research
session, or it kind of influences the
model in researching in the right way as
well, or at least the way that I like.
Spins up a background agent to do the
research so you keep working while it
reads. Investigate the question against
primary sources, write the findings to a
simple markdown file, and save it where
the repo already keeps such notes match
the existing convention. So this is
useful too if you need to do any
research, you can just invoke the
research skill and you're good to go.
The next one, of course, is the
prototype, which I've kind of shown off
a little bit before. I don't think I've
done a full video on it. This is now
modeling, folks, so that Wayfinder can
invoke it itself, and it essentially
gives you a choice between logic or
state. So it's either a logic prototype
or a UI prototype, and they react quite
differently. The final change is
something that people have been asking
for for a while, and I finally decided
to pull the trigger on it, which is
before in my TDD skill, it would
recommend a set of steps for you to
follow, and that was a little bit
awkward sometimes. The steps were like,
it would confirm what tests it wanted to
write with you, and then you would, you
know, walk it through, walk it through,
and it didn't fit with most people's
idea of how TDD should work, which is
you should be able to pass an AFK agent
the TDD skill, and it should just work.
And so this TDD skill is now reference
material only. So it doesn't specify any
particular steps apart from just the
order in which you should write tests
in, so to do red green refactor. So it's
just says red before green, one slice at
a time, and it also splits away
refactoring as as not part of the loop.
So it's no longer a red green refactor
loop, it's more just red green. I tend
to think that putting the refactoring in
the code review part is a lot more
productive because then you don't
overload the implementation. So that is
all of the changes that have come in on
the skills. It is a lot of changes, and
if you're nervous about missing any of
the updates, then I recommend that you
clear out all of your skills and do NPX
skills update and grab all of the new
ones. If you've made updates to your
skills in the meantime, then you can
just point your clanker at my repo and
just say pull down all of the good new
stuff, especially pointing at the
release notes. The thing I think this
release will be remembered for is to
spec and to tickets changing because
that is just a little bit of friction,
but I think good friction cuz it names
it properly. And I hope to be the start
of you getting obsessed with Wayfinder.
I'm using Wayfinder for literally
everything, even non-coding stuff. I've
actually been planning my next course
with Wayfinder and it's really, really
good. In fact, why don't I just show you
that course now? This is the AI coding
crash course. This is going to be
different from the cohorts that I
usually run. It's going to be much, much
cheaper and it's going to be self-paced
so you can purchase it anytime. You get
help from the Discord kind of in the
usual way, but it's not going to be
gated like a normal cohort. It is going
to be the perfect intro for anyone who's
looking to get into AI coding, whether
you are a developer or whether you are
not a developer. So, for senior
engineers, it's going to be a conversion
course. For folks who are new to
development, it's going to be the way
that you can actually get productive
using these crazy new tools. I've not
announced a price yet. I am going to
just be adding sign-ups in here and
it'll be available once I finish filming
it, maybe in about
August time, I think. But folks, thank
you so much for watching. It's always a
pleasure sharing these skills updates
with you. It is really cool to see the
usage just absolutely grow and grow.
Everyone tells me I shouldn't show the
star counts, but it's up to like 160K
stars now. Uh 7 million downloads on
skills.sh. It is just bonkers. So, thank
you so much for enjoying the skills. I
hope they are helping you ship more and
ship more productively and I'll see you
very soon.